-=THE LAST FANTASY=-
仅供交流 严禁商用
字幕来源：ljy2006ljy2006@shooter.com
字幕调校：EvineDeng
沃特·迪斯尼（Walt Disney）公司出品
星银岛  Treasure  Planet
旁白：在一个晴空万里的夜晚
NARRATOR: On the clearest of nights...
伊塞林上和风徐徐
when the winds of the Etherium were calm and peaceful...
满载大角星水晶的商船
the great merchant ships...with their cargoes of Arcturian sura crystals...
让人感觉那么安全
felt safe and secure.
谁也没想到， 他们早就被人盯上了
Little did they suspect that they were pursued by...
那就是海盗！
pirates.
这些海盗中最可怕就是
And the most feared of all these pirates...
声名狼藉的船长： 纳撒尼尔·弗林特
was the notorious Captain Nathaniel Flint.
开炮！
Fire!
啊！
Aah!
像只折翼的小鹰 承受着突如其来掠夺
Like a Candarian zap-wing overtaking its prey--
詹姆斯·普莱迪斯·霍金斯
James Pleiades Hawkins.
一小时前你就该去上床睡觉了.
I thought you were asleep an hour ago.
妈妈，我刚看到最精彩的部分
Mom, I was just getting to the best part.
求您了！
Please?
哦，精神百倍啊？
Oh, can those eyes get any bigger?
过去点
Scootch over.
旁白：像只折翼的小鹰
...Iike a Candarian zap-wing...
承受着突如其来掠夺
overtaking its prey...
弗林特和他的叛军
Flint and his band of renegades...
猛冲进去
swooped in out of nowhere.
哈 哈 哈 哈
Ha ha ha ha!
掠夺他们的战利品
And then. gathering up their spoils...
然后，消失得无影无踪
vanished without a trace.
-嚯！ -嚯！
-Ooh! -Ooh!
旁白：没人发现弗林特的秘密宝藏
Flint's secret trove was never found...
所有的传说都说那些宝藏仍藏在
but stories have persisted that it remains hidden...
银河中一个遥远的地方
somewhere at the farthest reaches of the galaxy...
藏匿着
stowed with riches beyond imagination--
自上千个星球掠夺来的巨大财富
the loot of a thousand worlds...
星银岛 星银岛
Treasure Planet.
好了，擤一下鼻涕
OK. Blow your nose.
妈妈，你觉得弗林特船长是怎么做到的？
How do you think Captain Flint did it, Mom?
他怎么冲下去后， 就消失得无影无踪呢？
How'd he swoop in out of nowhere and vanished without a trace?
我不知道
I have no idea.
过来，快快快
Come here, you, you li--
我要吹了！哦！
I'm gonna get--oh!
好了，该睡觉了
OK, now it's time for this
你觉得会有人找到星银岛吗？
You think somebody'll ever find Treasure Planet?
宝贝，我想
Sweetheart,
那只是一个传说
Iike a legend.
我知道那是真的
I know it's real.
好好，你说得对，那是真的
You win. It's real.
-晚安，妈妈！ -晚安，宝贝！
-Nighty-night, Mom. -Nighty-night, sweetheart.
我爱你！
I love you.
我也爱你！
Love you, too.
旁白：夜晚，伊塞林的风
There are nights when the winds of the Etherium...
自由自在的飞舞着
so inviting in their promise of flight and freedom...
令每个人情绪激昂！
made one's spirit soar!
十二年后
呀－呼！
Yaaaa-hoo!
呜呼——！
Whoo!
加速！
Come on!
呜呼——！哈哈哈哈！
Whoo! Ha ha ha!
呜呼——！
Whoo-hoo!
哦！我的天！
Oh, great.
（旅馆）
霍金斯夫人！
Mrs. Hawkins!
来了－ 把果汁装满
I know-- refill on the purp juice.
马上就来！敦莱蒂夫人！
Coming right up, Mrs. Dunwiddie.
上菜了，四份玻璃球粉
There we go. That's four powdered spheroids...
两份月蚀。 还有一大碗
two lunar eclipses, and it's a big bowl...
泽勒林果冻虫，给这个大男孩的！
of Zorellian jelly worms for the big boy!
-太好了！ -慢用！
-Awesome! -Enjoy.
对不起，德尔波特！ 今天早上这里闹哄哄的.
Sorry, Delbert. It's been a madhouse here all morning.
没事，莎拉！
No problem, Sarah.
啊，我的加种子的阿尔伯尼杂烩
Ah! My Alponian chowder with the extra solara seed.
呣——！
Mmm! Yum!
你好啊！
Hello.
你从哪来？
What brings you here...
好奇的小家伙？
curious little...one?
走吧！
Go away.
你爸妈呢？
Are your parents around?
怎么了？ 哑巴了？呀——！
What's the matter? Cat got your--yaah!
欧，这年纪的孩子真可爱！
Oh, they're so adorable at that age.
欧，是的！真可惜
Oh, yes...deplorable.
哦，是可爱！呣！
Uh...adorable! Hmm.
说起这个 吉姆怎么样了？
Speaking of which, how's Jim doing?
好多了。我知道年初
Much better. I know he had some rough spots...
他受到打击。 但我想
earlier this year, but I really think...
他会度过难关的！
that he's starting to turn a corner.
霍金斯夫人？
Mrs. Hawkins?
吉姆！
Jim!
哦，看来还没完
Ooh...wrong turn.
好了，谢谢你们送我回来！
OK. Thanks for the lift, guys.
别急！
Not so fast.
我们发现您的儿子
We apprehended your son operating...
在禁区里驾驶太阳能车
a solar vehicle in a restricted area.
违反了904条例中
Moving violation 9-0-4...
第15节
section fifteen,
第6？
Six?
-谢谢！ -不客气！
-Thank you. -Don't mention it.
-吉姆！ --您知道的
-Jim! -As you are aware, ma'am...
这是违反条例的
this constitutes a violation of his probation.
是的，是的！不！我明白。 呣，我们是不是可以....
Yes, yes. No, I understand. Um, but could we just--
嗯，打扰一下
Um. ahem. pardon me.
长官，我是不是可以说一句？
Officers, if I might, uh, interject here.
我是著名的物理学家， 德尔波特·多普勒博士
I am the noted astrophysicist Dr. Delbert Doppler.
你们应该听说过我
Perhaps you've heard of me.
不知道？嗯，我这里有个剪报！
No? Uh, I have a clipping.
-您是男孩的父亲？ -哦！我的天，不是！
-Are you the boy's father? -Oh! Good heavens, no!
哦！他是我们家的好朋友！
Eww! He's just an old friend of the family.
退回去，先生！
Back off, sir!
谢谢！德尔波特。 我会解决的！
Thank you, Delbert. I will take it from here.
好的，莎拉，如果你坚持这样...
Well, Sarah, if you insist.
啊咳，以后别让我这么做了
Ahem. Don't ever let me do that again.
由于他再三违反15C条例
Due to repeated violations of statute 1 5-C...
我们扣押了他的车子， 如果再犯
we have impounded his vehicle. Any more slip-ups will result...
我们定会将他送进少管所！
in a one-way ticket to Juvenile Hall.
-少儿监狱 -监狱
-Kiddie hoosegow. -The slammo.
谢谢长官！ 以后不会再发生了！
Thank you, officers. It won't happen again.
我们会时刻监视着他
We see his type all the time, ma'am.
-错误的选择. -终结者！
-Wrong choices. -Dead-enders.
失败者！
Losers.
-好自为之！ -我们走！
-You take care now. -Let's motor.
吉姆，我早就跟你说过了！
Jim, I have had it.
你真的想去少管所？ 是不是？
Do you want to go to Juvenile Hall? Is that it?
吉姆？
Jim?
吉姆，看着我！
Jim, look at me.
我辛辛苦苦维持这个旅馆
It's been hard enough keeping this place...
全是我一个人忙呼， 你做过什么？
afloat by myself without you going--
妈妈，别大惊小怪的！ 一直都是你一个人！
Mom, it's no big deal. There was nobody around.
那些警察只是把我的车子拿走了
Those cops just won't get off my--
算了吧
Forget it.
霍金斯夫人！我的果汁！
Mrs. Hawkins! My juice!
知道，我马上来！ 敦莱蒂夫人！
Yes, I'll be right there, Mrs. Dunwiddie.
吉姆，我只是不想看到你...
Jim, I just don't want to see you...
放弃自己的将来
throw away your entire future.
将来, 什么将来？
Yeah, what future?
难以想象你是怎么维持下来的，莎拉
I really don't know how you manage it. Sarah.
要经营生意， 还要带大一个像
Trying to run a business while raising a felon like--
像吉姆这样的孩子
felon...fellow... fellow like Jim.
维持？ 我已经没办法了
Managing it? I'm at the end of my rope.
对他父亲的离开
Ever since his father left...
吉姆一直都耿耿于怀
well. Jim's just never recovered.
你知道他有多聪明的
And you know how smart he is.
他八岁的时候 做了第一个太阳能滑板
He built his first solar surfer when he was eight!
之后，他就没上过学
And yet. he's failing at school...
他不断地惹麻烦
he is constantly in trouble...
跟他说话的时候， 他就像个陌生人
and when I talk to him. he's like a stranger to me.
我不知道为什么。德尔波特， 我已经尽力了！
I don't know. Delbert. I've tried everything--
嗨，先生！
Hey, Mister?
罐子里的先生，你还好吗？
Mister,
啊——！
Aah!
他马上来了
He's a-comin'.
你听到他说话了吗？
Can you hear him?
那些齿轮和陀螺呼呼的转着
Those gears and gyros clickin' and whirrin'...
就像那个恶魔一样！
Iike the devil himself!
哦，撞晕头了？
Uh, hit your head there pretty hard, didn't ya?
他来抢我的箱子
He's after me chest...
那个残忍的机器人 还有他的屠杀部队
that fiendish cyborg and his band of cutthroats.
但是他们必须
But they'll have to pry it...
先从比利·鲍恩斯冰冷的 死人的手指中探察
from old Billy Bones' cold, dead fingers afore l--argh!
哦，我的...
Oh, my--
哦，来吧，把胳膊给我
Uh, come on, give me your arm.
对了
That's it.
-好孩子。 -我这么做妈妈会很高兴的
-Good lad. -Mom's gonna love this.
德尔波特，感谢您听你我唠叨。
Thanks for listening, Delbert.
我好多了
It helps.
一切都会好的
It's going to be OK.
放心吧
You'll see.
我一直希望， 有一天我打开门...
I keep dreaming one day I'll open that door...
他会像以前一样
and there he'll be just the way he was.
一个开朗、快乐的男孩， 抱着一只新宠物...
A smiling, happy little boy, holding a new pet...
让我允许收留它
and begging me to let him keep it.
詹姆斯·普莱迪斯·霍金斯
James Pleiades Hawkins!
妈妈，他受伤了 伤得很重
Mom, he's hurt...bad!
我的箱子，小伙子
Me chest, lad.
他马上就来了
He'll be comin' soon.
不能让他找到这东西
Can't let them find this.
谁要来？
Who's coming?
机器人！
The cyborg!
小心那机器人！
Beware the cyborg!
哦！
Ohh!
快！我们必须马上离开这儿！
Quick! We gotta go!
-哦！ -啊！
-Ohh! -Aah!
我想这时候我离不开吉姆了！
I believe I'm with Jim on this one!
黛利拉！（原是圣经中人物） 哈利路亚！
Delilah! Hallelujah!
呆在那儿！ 别动！
Stay! Don't move!
那东西呢？
Where is it?!
把它找出来！
Find it!
不用担心，莎拉！
Don't worry. Sarah.
我是个物理学专家
I'm an expert in the laws of physical science.
-我们数到三。一... -三！
-On the count of three--one... -Three!
-啊！ -啊！
-Aah! -Aah!
快，黛利拉，快！
Go, Delilah! Go!
快走！对极了！快！
Go! That's it! That's it! Go!
驾！驾！
Hyah! Hyah!
我跟警察说了
I just spoke with the constabulary.
那些海盗逃走的时候 没有留下任何线索！
Those blaggard pirates have fled without a trace.
我很难过，莎拉！
I'm sorry, Sarah.
我想老本鲍旅馆已经化为灰烬了
I'm afraid the old Benbow lnn has burned to the ground.
对了， 都是那个小球带来的麻烦！
Ahem. Well, certainly a lot of trouble...over that odd little sphere.
那些标记看起来挺奇怪的
Those markings baffle me.
我从没见过像这样的东西
Unlike anything I've ever encountered.
就是以我丰富的经验
Even with my vast experience...
和惊人的智慧
and superior intellect...
都得花好几年才能打开它
it would take me years to unlock its--hey!
什么？是张地图！
Why, it's a map!
等等！等等！
Wait. Wait, wait, wait!
这是我们，在特雷斯普行星
This is us,
那是麦哲伦云层
That's the Magellanic Cloud!
哦！珊瑚星系！
Whoo! The Coral Galaxy!
哦！
Oh!
那是天鹅星座！
That's the Cygnus Cross...
克里安黑洞！
and that's the Kerian Abyss.
等等！这是什么？这是什么？ 奇怪，它是...
Wait. What's this? What's this? Why, it--it's...
星银岛！
Treasure Planet.
不！
No!
是星银岛！
That's Treasure Planet!
弗林特的宝藏？
Flint's trove?
掠夺上千个世界的战利品？
The loot of a thousand worlds?
你知道这意味着什么吗？
You know what this means?
就是说所有的财宝只是在一艘船上。
It means that all that treasure is only a boat ride away.
有了它就有了全世界
Whoever brings it back would hold an eternal place...
高高的站在万神殿上受万人朝拜！ 想必他就是这样！
atop the pantheon of explorers! He'd be able to experience--
哦！刚才怎么了？
Whoo! What just happened?
妈妈，就是这个！ 这是所有问题的答案！
Mom, this is it. This is
吉姆，这绝对不可能！
Jim, there is
您还记得那些故事吗？
Don't you remember, all those stories?
就是了，他们只是故事！
That's all they were--stories!
有了那些财宝
With that treasure...
我们可以建造数百个本鲍旅馆
we could rebuild the Benbow a hundred times over!
哦，这是...这到底是...
Well, this is--
德尔波特，你可以解释这个荒谬的事情？
Delbert, would you please explain how ridiculous this is?
真是太荒谬了
It's totally preposterous...
一个人穿过整个星系
traversing the entire galaxy alone.
好了，现在乖乖呆在这儿吧
Now at last,
-所以我要和你一起去！ -德尔波特！
-That's why I'm going with you. -Delbert!
用我的积蓄来作为探险队的费用
I'll use my savings to finance the expedition.
我要搞艘船， 雇一个船长还有一个水手队！
I'll commission a ship, hire a captain and a crew.
你不是认真的吧？
You're not serious.
我这辈子就等这么个机会了
All my life I've been waiting for an opportunity like this...
我听到了一个声音： “前进吧，德尔波特！前进吧，德尔波特”
and here it is screaming, "Go, Delbert! Go, Delbert!"
好了，好了！ 你们两个都疯了！
OK. OK! You're both grounded!
妈妈，你看
Mom. Iook...
我知道我让这里乱七八糟的
I know that I keep messing everything up...
我知道
and I know...
我让你失望
that I let you down.
但这是我向你证明我自己的机会
But this is my chance to make it up to you.
我会把一切处理的妥妥当当的
I'm gonna set things right.
莎拉？
Sarah?
可以吗？
If I may?
你说你已经没办法了
You said yourself, you've tried everything.
没有比在太空中锻炼的几个月
There are much worse remedies...
更好的补救方法了
than a few character-building months in space.
你这么说是因为 这么做是对的
Are you saying this because it's the right thing...
还是因为你真的想去？
or because you really want to go?
真的，真的，真的， 真的想去
I really, really, really, really want to go...
而且这么做是对的！
and it's the right thing.
吉姆
Jim...
我不想失去你
I don't want to lose you.
妈妈，我也舍不得
Mom...you won't.
我不会让你失望的
I'll make you proud.
好了，哦
Well. uh. ahem.
我们这不是在一起吗？
There we are then.
我们马上开始准备
We'll begin preparations at once.
吉姆，我的孩子， 我们马上要升上太空了
Jim, my boy, soon we'll be off to the spaceport.
吉姆，等等我！
Jim! Oh. Jim! Wait for me!
哦，吉姆，我们
Well, Jim, this should be
应该好好的互相了解一下
for the two of us to get to know one another.
你知道他们说什么， 亲情沟通，呣
You know what they say, familiarity breeds, um...
这样说不太礼貌 但是，在我么看来...
well, contempt, but, in our case--
走吧，找找我们的船！
Look, let's just find the ship. OK?
-你右手边的第二个泊位！ -你可以找到的！
-Second berth on your right! -You can't miss it.
嘿，谢谢！
Hey, thanks.
合适吗？
It's the suit, isn't it?
那个可恶的女店员！
to that pushy two-headed saleswoman.
这个说合适！
This one said it fit,
哦不知道该怎么办。 我都有些混乱了！哦！
I didn't know what to do. I get so flustered. Ooh!
欧，吉姆！这是我们的船！ R.L.S.的遗产！
Oh, Jim! This is our ship! The R.L.S. Legacy!
哇！
Whoa!
把这些桶搬上去！
Stow those casks forward!
拉上去！
Heave together now!
太酷了！
How cool is this?
对不起，我是说...
Sorry about that. I didn't mean--
让我来
Allow me to handle this.
吉姆，我的弗拉图拉语很流利！
I'm fluent in Flatula, Jim.
我在大学里学了两年！
Took two years of it in high school.
弗拉图拉？太酷了！
Flatula? Cool.
早上好，船长！ 都准备好了吗？
Good morning, Captain. Everything shipshape?
都准备好了，先生！ 但是我不是船长！
Shipshape it is, sir, but I'm not the captain.
船长在上面！
The captain's aloft.
埃柔先生，我已经
Mr. Arrow, I've checked
上上下下检查过了
from stem to stern,
你怎么都不会出点错？
Can you get nothing wrong?
您过讲了，船长
You flatter me, Captain.
啊，多普勒博士，我没认错吧？
Ah, Dr. Doppler, I presume?
哦，是的，我...
Uh, um, yes. I--
-你好啊，你能听到我说话吗？ -是的，我可以，不要再敲了！
-Hello! Can you hear me? -Yes, I can! Stop that banging!
博士，这东西使用时
If I may, Doctor, this works so much better...
可以工作的更好
when it's right-way up and plugged in.
-哦！ -你真是太可爱了！
-Ooh! -Lovely. There you go.
您要是不介意， 我想我可以自己来控制
If you don't mind, I can manage my own plugging!
我是阿米莉娅船长
I'm Captain Amelia...
普洛腾舰队的后起之秀
Iate of a few run-ins with the Protean armada.
龌龊的买卖， 但我不想因我的创伤烦扰你
Nasty business, but I won't bore you with my scars.
您已经见过我的助手了 ——埃柔先生
You've met my first officer, Mr. Arrow.
淳朴，强壮，可靠， 诚实，勇猛，忠实
Sterling, tough, dependable, honest, brave, and true.
行了，船长
Please, Captain.
哦，闭嘴，埃柔！ 我是说你一样都不是
Oh, shut up, Arrow. You know I don't mean a word of it.
啊哈，打扰一下。 我不喜欢打断人家！
Ahem, excuse me. I hate to interrupt. It's not much better.
但是，我可以跟你们介绍， 吉姆·霍金斯
but may I introduce to you, Jim Hawkins?
吉姆，你们知道， 就是找到那些珍宝的男孩
Jim, you see, is the boy who found the treasure--
博士，够了！
Doctor, please!
到我船舱来， 我跟你谈谈
I'd like a word with you in my stateroom.
博士，在这些多嘴的人面前
Doctor, to muse and blabber about the treasure now
说这些关于财宝的事情
in front of this particular crew...
只能说明
demonstrates a level of ineptitude...
你简直就是一个低能儿
that borders on the imbecilic...
这么说，我已经是很人道了
and I mean that in a very caring way.
低能？你这么说我？ 愚蠢，我..
Imbecilic, did you say? Foolishness, I've--
我可以看看地图吗？
May I see the map, please?
看吧
Here.
呣，太好了
Hmm. Fascinating.
霍金斯先生，以后
Mr. Hawkins, in the future...
你可以叫我“船长”或者是“先生”
you will address me as "Captain" or "Ma'am."
明白了吗？
Is that clear?
啊
Ugh...
霍金斯先生？
Mr. Hawkins?
-知道了，先生
-Yes, ma'am.
先生们，这东西不用的时候， 我们必须把它锁起来
Gentlemen, this must be kept under lock and key...
博士，我用我最诚挚的敬意 再说一遍
when not in use. And, Doctor, again...with the greatest possible respect...
不要再大声嚷嚷！
zip your howling screamer.
船长，我保证
Captain, I assure you l--
我简短的说一下
Let me make this as monosyllabic as possible.
我不在乎你雇用的这些水手
I don't much care for this crew you hired.
他们...埃柔， 你说我要怎么形容这些人？
They're...how did l describe them, Arrow?
早茶之前我说得很清楚了
I said something rather good this morning before coffee.
“一帮滑稽可笑的留着口水的傻子！”先生
"A ludicrous parcel of driveling galoots," ma'am.
-就是这样！太有诗意了！ -现在，看着我
-There you go--poetry. -Now, see here--
博士，我想和所有的船员聊天
Doctor, I'd love to chat to the whole ship crew.
但是，我得负责这艘船的航行
but I have a ship to launch...
你也擦亮了你的装备
and you've got your outfit to buff up.
埃柔先生，请你把这两个新人
Mr. Arrow, please escort these two neophytes...
带下去
down to the galley straightaway.
年轻的霍金斯就跟着 我们的厨师席尔瓦先生
Young Hawkins will be working for our cook, Mr. Silver.
什么？厨师？
What? The cook?
死女人，属猫的！
That woman! That...feline!
她搞清楚谁才是头儿了没有？
Who does she think is working for whom?
那是我的地图， 她是拿我的工钱的！
It's my map, and she's got me bussin' tables?
不许你们说我船长的坏话！
I'll not tolerate a cross word about our captain!
再也找不到比她更好的长官了！
There's no finer officer in this or any galaxy.
席尔瓦先生？
Mr. Silver?
怎么了？埃柔先生？
Why, Mr. Arrow, sir.
您的到来
Bringin' in such fine and distinguished gents...
使这里蓬荜生辉
to grace my humble galley.
您有何指示？
Had I known,
呵呵呵呵
Heh heh heh heh!
机器人！
A cyborg!
这是多普勒博士！
May I introduce Dr. Doppler?
我们此次航行的投资者
The financier of our voyage.
博士，您装备很可爱
Lovely outfit, Doc.
哦，谢谢！ 您的眼睛也很不错！
Well, thank you. Um, lovely eye.
这个小家伙是吉姆·霍金斯
Uh, this young lad is Jim Hawkins.
吉姆！哦...
Jimbo! Uh...
啊，不要被这大家伙吓着了
Aw, now, don't be too put off by this hunk of hardware.
哇！
Whoa!
这装置可以用来...
These gears have been tough getting used to...
但是他们的确很方便
but they do come in mighty handy from time to time.
呣！
Mmm!
好了，来，尝尝！
Here, now, have a taste
呣！我喜欢这味道， 浓烈的味道
Mmm! Delightfully tangy, yet robust.
祖传秘方！
Old family recipe.
啊！
Aah!
实际上，那是祖传秘方中的一部分！
In fact, that was part of the old family!
哈哈哈哈！
Ha ha ha!
欧欧欧！博士，我只是开个玩笑！
Oh, ho! I'm just kiddin', Doc!
哦，是的，没事
Uh, yeah, well...
我要不开玩笑， 那不就是我了
I'm nothin' if I ain't a kidder.
喝吧，吉姆！
Go on, Jimbo. Have a swig.
墨菲！
Morph!
你这个淘气的水滴！
You jiggle-headed blob of mischief!
你刚才藏哪儿去了？
So that's where you was hiding!
哇！哈！ 这是什么？
Wha--? Ha! What is that thing?
“这是什么？”
"What is that thing?"
他是个变种！
He's a morph.
我在变体1中装了形状转换装备
I rescued the little shape-shifter on Proteus 1.
啊哈，他看上我了
Aw, he took a shine to me.
我们一直在一起
We been together ever since.
好极了，啊，乖孩子
Right? Yeah. Nice boy.
走吧，我们下去吧
We're about to get underway.
博士，您要不要参观一下这艘飞船？
Would you like to observe the launch, doctor?
我可以吗？
Would l?
现在的星系核有超光速飞机吗？
Does an active galactic nucleus have superluminal jets?
你带路！
I'll follow you.
席尔瓦先生， 霍金斯先生留在这里听你的指示！
Mr. Hawkins will stay here in your charge, Mr. Silver.
先生，您能再说一遍吗？
Beggin' your pardon, sir, but--
这是船长的命令， 别让这个新来的服务生闲着！
Captain's orders! See to it the new cabin boy's kept busy.
-啊，但是不行...
-Aw, but, no, but--
这样，船长让你和我在一起？
So, Captain's put you with me, eh?
不管怎么样
Whatever.
我一个低贱的机器人 是不能和船长争论的
Well, who be a humble cyborg to argue with a captain?
是的
Yeah.
你知道的，这些小狗
You know...these purps...
他们就像是 从蒙特里莎回来的一样
they're kind of like the ones back home on Montressor.
你去过那儿？
You ever been there?
吉姆，不能说是我去过
I can't say as I have, Jimbo.
仔细想想
Come to think of it,
我碰到这个老家伙
I met this old guy, who was, um...
他在找他的机器人伙伴
he was kind of looking for a cyborg buddy of his.
是吗？
Is that so?
是的
Yeah.
那人叫什么名字？
What was that old salamander's name?
哦，哦，鲍恩斯
Oh, yeah. Bones.
比利·鲍恩斯？
Billy Bones?
鲍恩斯？鲍恩斯？
Bones? Bones?!
呣，他有摇铃吗？
Mm-mmm. T'ain't ringin' any bells.
一定是另外一个机器人！
Must have been a different cyborg.
在这艘船上还有许多机器人
There's a slew of cyborgs roamin' this port.
准备起飞！
Prepare to cast off!
哦，去吧，小伙子， 去看看起飞吧
Eh, off with you, lad, and watch the launch.
还有许多工作等着你做呢
There'll be plenty work a-waitin' for you afterwards.
我们最好盯着这个男孩， 是不是，墨菲？
We best be keepin' a sharp eye on this one, eh, Morph?
我们不能让他多管闲事！
We wouldn't want him strayin' into things he shouldn't.
船长，我们都准备好了
We're all clear, Captain!
哦，朋友， 我们是不是可以让这破船起飞了？
Well, my friend. Are we ready to raise this creaking tub?
船长，荣幸之至！
My pleasure, Captain.
各就各位！
All hands to stations!
快点！
Smartly now!
快点，你这个渣仔！ 我要追上你！
Come on, you scurvy scum! I'll race you!
打开所有太阳能帆！
Loose all solar sails!
快！
Come on!
把帆拉紧！
Heave up the braces.
拉紧！
Brace up.
哦，哦！
Ooh. Oh.
佐夫先生，加强船的吸引力
Mr. Zoff, engage the dropt
腾巴克先生，南偏西， 转向：2－1－0－0
South by southwest, Mr. Turnbuckle, heading 2-1-0-0.
是，船长。2－1－0－0
Aye, Captain. 2-1-0-0.
全速前进。埃柔先生！
Full speed, Mr. Arrow, if you please.
全速前进！
Take her away!
博士，您能不能坚强一点？
Brace yourself, Doctor.
“您能不能坚强一点？”
"Brace yourself."
啊！哦！
Aah! Oof!
哇！
Whoa.
难以置信 这就是冥界的银河？
Upon my word, an Orcus Galacticus.
笑一个
Smile.
哦，博士，你最好站远点
Uh, Doctor, I'd stand clear--
哈
Ha.
啊，船长 真是航运史上一个伟大的日子
Ah. 'tis a grand day for sailing. Captain...
看看您
and look at you.
您衣冠楚楚，就像
You're as trim and as bonny as a sloop...
一艘上了新帆， 涂了新漆的帆船
with new sails and a fresh coat of paint.
席尔瓦先生， 你可以把你的这些恭维
You can keep that kind of flim-flammery...
送给那些在空间站的妓女
for your spaceport floozies, Silver.
飞船基地的妓女 飞船基地的妓女
Spaceport floozy, spaceport floozy--
船长，你也太打击我了
You cut me to the quick, Captain.
我一直有什么说什么
I speaks nothing but me heart at all times.
自是肺腑之言
Nothing but me heart.
对了，那是你的帮手吗？
And, by the way, isn't that your cabin boy...
在桅杆上闲逛的？
aimlessly footling about in those shrouds?
是的，他...哦
Yep, it--oh...
只是一时的失误，船长！ 马上就会恢复正常！吉姆！
A momentary aberration, Cap'n, soon to be addressed. Jimbo!
我新交了两个朋友， 我想你见见他们
I got two new friends I'd like you to meet.
跟拖把先生和水桶小姐问好吧
Say hello to Mr. Mop and Mrs. Bucket.
呵呵呵呵！
Heh heh heh heh!
好啊
Yippee.
好了，我认识拖把先生了
Yeah, I got your Mr. Mop.
小心点，笨蛋
Watch it, twerp.
看什么看，怪物！
What are you looking at, weirdo?
就是，怪物
Yeah, weirdo.
服务生要学会 专心干自己的事！
Cabin boys should learn to mind their own business.
为什么？你把什么东西藏起来了？ 亮眼睛的家伙？
Why? You got something to hide, bright eyes?
看来你的耳朵有问题
Maybe your ears don't work so well.
是的，啊
Yeah. Ahem.
坏透了， 但是我的鼻子却很正常
Too bad my nose works just fine.
什么！你这个没有家教的家伙！
Why, you impudent little--
继续，把他剁了！
Go ahead! Slice him! Dice him!
你再说一遍？服务生！
Any last words, cabin boy?
斯科洛先生
Mr. Scroop...
你知道
you ever see what happens to a fresh purp...
狗被用力掐的下场吗？
when you squeeze real hard?
出什么事了！
What's all this. then?
你们知道规矩的
You know the rules.
船上不许大声喧哗
There'll be no brawling on this ship.
是的，是的，先生
Aye, aye, sir.
以后谁要再犯，
Any further offenders will be confined to the brig...
就只能呆在狭窄的双桅船里了
for the remainder of the voyage.
斯科洛先生， 我说得够明白吗？
Am I clear, Mr. Scroop?
知道了
Transparently.
做的好，埃柔先生！
Well done, Mr. Arrow, sir!
一艘团结的船， 一艘令人愉快的船！
A tight ship's a happy ship, sir.
吉姆，给你个活干！
Jimbo, I gave you a job.
嘿，之前我一直在做！
Hey, I was doing it until that bug thing--
闭嘴， 现在我要你把甲板拖的干干净净
Belay that! Now, I want this deck swabbed spotless...
我回来之前还没做好， 你就祈求上帝保佑吧
and heaven help you if I come back and it's not done.
墨菲， 看着这小子
Morph? Keep an eye on this pup...
随时留意着他有没有分心
and let me know if there be any more distractions.
是，遵命！
OK. Aye-aye.
好了，大家都到齐了
So, we're all here, then.
-来了 -很好
-Excuse me. -Fine.
先生们，请原谅我的坦率
Now, if you pardon my plain speaking, gentlemen...
你们都是
are you all...
笨蛋， 彻彻底底的蠢货吗！？
stark-raving, totally blinking daft?!
我好不容易让大家
After all me finagling getting us hired...
以水手的身份上船
as an upstanding crew...
你们想让计划全部败露吗？
you want to blow the whole mutiny before it's time?
那男孩已经有所察觉了！
The boy was sniffing about.
是你差点让计划失败的，笨蛋！
You just stick to the plan, you bug-brained twit.
至于那个小孩， 我会给他一堆的活儿
As for the boy, I'll run him so ragged...
让他没有时间去想
he won't have time to think.
这真是有趣的一天
Well, this has been a fun day
交了新朋友，像那个蜘蛛
Making new friends like that spider psycho.
蜘蛛，蜘蛛
Spider psycho, spider psycho.
呵呵，有点丑
Heh. A little uglier.
哈哈哈哈
Mwah-ha-ha-ha!
闭上嘴吧
Pretty close.
哦
Well...
这真要感谢上帝了
thank heavens for little miracles.
上来一个小时了
Up here for an hour...
甲板还是老样子
and the deck's still in one piece.
嗯，你知道，哦
Um, look, l, uh...
你所做的
What you did...
谢谢
Thanks.
难道没人教你
Didn't your pap ever teach you...
要好好控制自己的情绪吗？
to pick your fights a bit more carefully?
你父亲没有教你？
Your father's not the teachin' sort.
没有！
No.
他离家出走了， 再也没回来！
He was more the taking off and never coming back sort.
哦！
Oh.
对不起，小伙子
Sorry, lad.
嘿，没事 我很好
Hey, no big deal. I'm doing just fine.
真的？
Is that so?
既然船长把你安排在我这里
Well, since the captain has put you in my charge...
不管我喜不喜欢你
Iike it or not,
都不能让你惹上麻烦
into that thick head of yours to keep you out of trouble.
-什么？ -从现在起
-What? -From now on...
我会一直盯着你
I'm not letting you out of me sight.
你不能这么做！
You can't do--
你不能想吃就吃 想睡就睡
You won't so much as eat, sleep...
没我同意的话， 你什么都不许做
or scratch your bum without my say-so.
你别在这儿给我出馊主意！
Don't do me any favors!
哦，小伙子， 你要相信我！
Oh, you can be sure of that, my lad.
相信我！
You can be sure of that.
哈哈哈哈！
Heh heh heh heh!
用点力气
Put some elbow into it.
（歌词） 爱通往神秘的地方
I am a question to the world
我不清楚的方向
Not an answer to be heard
跌跌撞撞，会不会鲁莽
Or a moment that's held in your arms
星光照亮苍白的天堂
And what do you think you'd ever say
燃烧胆怯的魔杖
I won't listen anyway
一股力量
You don't know me
在推着我体会冒险
And I'll never be what you want
的真相
Made of pain
勇敢口袋唯一的行囊
And what do you think you'd understand?
对抗没落的权杖
I'm a boy. no. I'm a man
面对风暴绝对不投降
You can take me and throw me away
飞翔迎着空气的冰凉
And how can you learn what's never shown
心却越烧越滚烫
Yeah. you stand here on your own
这趟旅程不会一样
They don't know me
宝藏葬在风暴的港湾
'Cause I'm not here
我在怀疑，我在想
And I want a moment to be real
不够坚强，别和他较量
Want to touch things I don 't feel
宝藏，没有清楚的模样
Want to hold on and feel I belong
没有真实的重量
And how can the world want me to change
依然发现终生难忘
They're the ones that stay the same
伙伴还有几个在身旁
They don 't know me
同样坚持和倔强
But I'm still here
不曾遗忘当初的信仰
And you see the things they never see
尽管路途遥远而漫长
All you wanted. I could be
充满未知和虚幻
Now you know me
只要记得
And I'm not afraid
你至诚的我在手上
And I want to tell you who I am
宝藏葬在风暴的港湾
Can you help me be a man?
我在怀疑，我在想
They can 't break me
不够坚强，别和他较量
As long as I know who I am
宝藏，没有清楚的模样
They can 't tell me who to be
没有真实的重量
'Cause I'm not what they see
依然发现终生难忘
Yeah. the world is still sleeping
手里紧握藏宝图
While I keep on dreaming for me
背诵你的祝福
城市一点点一点点
And the words are just whispers and lies
慢慢消失
That I'll never believe
勇气渐渐的渐渐的
And I want a moment to be real
写成故事
Want to touch things I don 't feel
宝藏葬在风暴的港湾
Want to hold on and feel I belong
哇！
Whoa!
我在怀疑我在想
How can you say I never change?
不够坚强别和他较量
They're the ones that stay the same
宝藏没有清楚的模样
I'm the one now
没有真实的重量
'Cause I'm still here
依然拥有终生难忘
I'm the one son still here
那宝藏是成长
I'm still here
是成长，是成长，在成长
哦，哦，哦！
Oh, ho ho!
你有麻烦了？
You having a little trouble there?
哦，离我远点！
Oh, get away from me.
哦，吉姆
Oh, Jimbo.
我在你这年纪的时候要是会开船
If I could maneuver a skiff like that when I was your age...
那今天走街上， 他们都会向我鞠躬
they'd be bowing in the streets when I walked by today.
在街上鞠躬
Bowing in the streets.
-噢。 -噢。
-Oof. -Oof.
我不知道
I don't know.
我离开家的时候 他们并没有对我表示赞扬。
They weren't exactly singing my praises when I left home.
-呵。喔。 -喔。
-Heh. Whew. -Whew.
但是我要改变这一切
But I'm gonna change all that.
现在？怎么改变？
Are you now? How so?
哦，我有计划。
Uh, I got some plans.
让他们对我刮目相看
Gonna make people see me a little different.
哦
Ooh.
有时，人算不如天算
Sometimes, plans go astray.
这一次不会
Not this time.
呣
Hmm.
哦
Ooh...
欧，谢谢，墨菲
Oh, thank you, Morphy.
哦，为什么
So, uh, how that happened anyway
你放弃了许多事情， 来实现一个梦想
You give up a few things chasing a dream.
值吗？
Was it worth it?
呵
Heh.
我希望如此，吉姆
I'm hoping it is, Jimbo.
我一直坚信
I most surely am.
怎么回事？
What the devil?
我的天
Good heavens.
是流星雨
The star Pelusa...
是超新星
it's gone supernova!
紧急回避，腾巴克先生
Evasive action, Mr. Turnbuckle!
是 ，船长
Aye-aye, Captain.
所有人，把自己的救生索绑好了 各就各位
All hands,
埃柔先生，收帆
Mr. Arrow, secure those sails!
收帆
Secure all sails!
伙计们，把它们都收下来
Reef them down. men!
吔，宝贝！击中了！ 哈哈哈哈！
Yeah, baby! Ba-boom! Ha ha ha ha!
-啊！ -席尔瓦！
-Aah! -Silver!
哇！谢谢！伙计！
Whoa. Thanks, lad.
船长，那颗星...
Captain, the star!
它飞向了一个...
It's devolving into a...
一个黑——洞！
a black hole!
我们就要被拉进去了！ 哦！
We're being pulled in! Ohh!
不，不行！
No, you don't, you--
这见鬼的波浪！ 他们太奇怪了！
Blast these waves! They're so deucedly erratic!
不，船长。 他们是有规律的！
No, Captain. They're not erratic at all.
四秒钟之后还有一波！
There'll be one more in precisely 4  seconds.
后面还有一个更大的
Followed by the biggest magilla of them all!
当然，聪明的博士！
Of course! Brilliant, Doctor!
我们可以借助最后一波的冲力 离开这里
We'll ride that last magilla out of here.
船长，帆都收好了！
All sails secured, Captain!
好样的！ 现在把它们全部打开！
Good man! Now release them immediately!
遵命，船长！ 你们都听到了，伙计们！
Aye, Captain. You heard her, men.
把帆全部展开
Unfurl those sails.
-什么？！ -我们刚刚收起来！
-What?! -But we just finished...
-坚持住！ -一定要坚持住！
-Tying them down! -Make up your blooming minds!
霍金斯先生！
Mr. Hawkins...
确定所有救生索的结都打紧了！
make sure all lifelines are secured good and tight!
遵命，船长
Aye-aye, Captain.
很结实，船长！
Lifelines secured, Captain!
好极了！
Very good!
哇！啊——！
Gaah! Whoa!
喔！
Oof!
啊！
Aah!
船长，最后一波了！
Captain. the last wave!
它来了！
Here it comes!
先生们，抓紧你们的救生索！
Hold on to your lifelines, gents!
下面的航行会很颠簸！
It's gonna be a bumpy ride!
喔！
Oof!
船长！哦，我的天。那是..
Captain! That--oh, my goodness. That was--
那真是.. 那是最...
that was absolutely-- that was the most--
哦
Oh, tish-tosh.
你天文学的建议功劳最大了
your astronomical advice was most helpful.
哦，哦，谢谢。 非常感谢！
Well, uh, uh--thank you. Thank you very much.
哦，我可以在解剖学上提供帮助
Well, I have a lot of help to offer anatomically--
解剖学，解剖学
amanamonically-- as-astronomically.
对了，席尔瓦先生， 我该恭喜你
Well, I must congratulate you, Mr. Silver.
你的服务生男孩
It seems your cabin boy...
在救生索上做了很大贡献啊
did a bang-up job with those lifelines.
所有人都做的很好
All hands accounted for,
埃柔先生？
Mr. Arrow?
我想埃柔先生失踪了
I'm afraid Mr. Arrow has been lost.
他的救生索没有绑紧
His lifeline was not secured.
不可能，我都检查了
No, I checked them all.
我..我的确都检查过了！ 他们都很牢靠！.
I--I did. I checked them all. They were secure.
我发誓！
I swear.
埃柔先生是个...
Mr. Arrow was a...
啊，很好的宇航员
Ahem. Fine spacer...
我们中最好的 是我们的榜样
finer than most of us could ever hope to be...
他知道这有风险
but he knew the risks,
回到你们的岗位上， 我们继续前进
Resume your posts. We carry on.
你知道吗？ 那不是你的错！
It weren't your fault, you know?
怎么了，如果不是你 一半的人会被卷进黑洞的
Why, half the crew would be spinning in that black abyss--
你还不明白了吗？ 是我把事情弄糟了
Look, don't you get it?! I screwed up!
只需两秒钟
For two seconds,
我本可以把事情做好，但是...
I could do something right, but--
啊！我只是...
Aagh! I just--
算了！算了！
Just forget it. Forget it.
现在，听我说， 詹姆斯·霍金斯
Now, you listen to me, James Hawkins.
年轻人，虽然你有本事
You got the makings of greatness in ya...
但你必须为自己的理想掌舵
but you gotta take the helm and chart your own course.
好好努力
Stick to it,
机会来时
and when the time comes you get the chance...
你就可以检验自己所做的了
to really test the cut of your sails...
向他们展示你努力的成果 我希望我能看到
and show what you're made of, well, I hope I'm there...
抓住机会，你大有前途
catching some of the light coming off ya that day.
呵呵
There, there.
小伙子，好了，吉姆
Lad, it's all right, Jimbo.
好了
It's all right.
不，吉姆，哦...
Now, Jim, l, um...
我得去值班了
I best be getting about my watch...
你得回去睡觉了
and you best be getting some shut-eye.
我深陷其中了，墨菲
Getting in too deep here, Morphy.
他们会说我越来越心软了
Next thing ya know, they'll be saying I've gone soft.
哦，欧！哦，欧！
Uh--oh! Oh! Ugh!
墨菲？
Morph?
墨菲，别闹了 天还没亮呢
Morph, knock it off. It's too early for this.
哦！嘿，墨菲！
Ow! Hey, Morph!
-嘿，回来！ -回来！
-Hey, come back here! -Come back here!
抓到你了，墨菲！
Gotcha, Morph!
够了，小鱿鱼！
That's it, you little squid.
小鱿鱼！ 小鱿鱼！
You little squid. You little squid.
鱿鱼！鱿鱼！鱿鱼！鱿鱼！
Squid. Squid. Squid. Squid.
哦！哦！
Ungh! Unh!
哈！你完了！
Ha! Busted!
我们要说的是我们等不及了！
Look. what we're saying is we're sick of all this waiting.
他们只剩三个了！
There's only three of them left.
我们就等着行动了
We are wanting to move.
在拿到珍宝之前， 我们不能行动
We don't move till we got the treasure in hand.
我是说把他们全杀了
I say we kill 'em all now.
这里我说的算！
I say what's to say!
埃柔先生已经死了
Disobey my orders again...
再违背我的命令
Iike that stunt you pulled with Mr. Arrow...
你的下场就和他一样！
and so help me, you'll be joining him!
言重了， 我知道
Strong talk, but I know otherwise.
斯科洛，你要说什么？
You got something to say. Scroop?
那个男孩
It's that boy.
我发现你对他很温柔
Methinks you have a soft spot for him.
是啊
Yeah.
现在，看着我，你们
Now, mark me, the lot of ya.
我只关心一件事， 只有一件事！
I care about one thing, and one thing only!
弗林特的宝藏！
Flint's trove.
你们以为我会因为
You think I'd risk it all for the sake...
这个小孩子，放弃吗？
of some nose-wiping little whelp?
那现在怎么办？
What was it now?
你在这年轻人身上投入了太多
"Oh. you got the makings of greatness in ya. "
闭嘴！
Shut your yap!
我只是让他惬意， 不至于察觉我们的事情
I cozied up to that kid to keep him off our scent.
我不会心软
But I ain't gone soft.
发现大陆了
Land ho!
哈哈哈，就在那里
Ha ha ha! There it is!
你们到了那里 就可以一饱眼福了
Feast eyes and click heels if you got 'em.
我的望远镜呢？
Where the devil's me glass?
吉姆
Jimbo.
我们在捉迷藏？
Playing games, are we?
是的
Yeah.
是的，我们是在捉迷藏
Yeah, we're playing games.
哦，我明白了， 好了，我从不放弃
Oh, I see. Well, I was never
我讨厌失败
Always hated to lose.
呣
Hmm.
我也是！
Me, too!
啊——！
Yaaah!
右边
Right-o...
哦，计划全乱了
Ohh...blast it all.
伙计们，计划有变
Change in plan, lads!
现在马上行动
We move now!
挂上我们的旗帜，奥讷斯先生
Strike our colors, Mr. Onus.
非常高兴，船长先生
With pleasure, Captain.
我船上有海盗？ 我要杀光他们！
Pirates on my ship? I'll see they all hang.
博士，会玩这东西吗？
Doctor, familiar with these?
哦，我见过
Oh, I've seen--
哦，不不不，我不会
Uh, no. No. No, I'm not.
哦
Ooh.
霍金斯先生，你死都要保住它
Mr. Hawkins! Defend this with your life.
墨菲，把它给我
Morph! Give me that!
哦，你们已经等了很久了
Oh, you're taking all day about it.
哦，拦住他们
Oh! Stop them!
啊，啊，啊喔！
Aah, aah, aah. Oof!
喔呼
Ooh hoo hoo!
嘿，你！
Hey, you!
到艇上去，快！
To the longboats, quickly!
啊！
Unh!
吔！
Rrr-yeah!
墨菲，不要！
Morph! No!
看这边！
Chew on this,
你瞄准了打的？
Did you actually aim for that?
实际上，我的确瞄准了！
You know, actually, I did.
哦，完了
Oh, blast it.
博士，我说“现在”的时候 把前面那缆绳打断
Doctor, when I say "now", shoot out the forward cable.
放心吧，我做得到
I'll take this one.
墨菲，这里，墨菲
Morph. here! Morph!
墨菲！
Morph!
墨菲，过来！
Morphy, come here.
墨菲，墨菲，过来！ 墨菲，过来
Morph. Morph. Bring it here. Morph, come here.
过来，过来，乖！ 回到父亲这里！.
Come here. Come here, boy. Come to your dad.
墨菲，过来
Come here, boy. Morph!
-过来这边！ -墨菲，墨菲，这里！
-Come on! -Morph! Morph, here!
-墨菲！ -墨菲！
-Morphy! -Morph!
欧！
Ohh.
现在！
Now!
哇！
Whoa!
啊！
Unh!
吉姆！
Jim!
参数正确 水力学派上用场了
Parameters met. Hydraulics engaged.
找到了，来爸爸这吧
That's it! Come to papa!
不要开炮！ 地图在他们身上！
Hold your fire! We'll lose the map!
船长！ 激光球在12点钟方向！
Captain! Laser ball at 12 o'clock!
-哇！ -啊！
-Whoa! -Aah!
哦
Ow.
哦，我的天
Oh, my goodness.
太好玩了， 我都想再来一次
That was more fun than I ever want to have again.
这不是我最成功的着陆！
That's not one of my...gossamer landings. Unh!
船长！
Captain!
哦！
Oh. Ooh.
哦，不要大惊小怪！
Oh, don't fuss.
哦
Uh-uh--
只是小伤，没事
Slight bruising. That's all.
来杯茶， 我马上就会好了
Cup of tea, and I'll be right as rain.
霍金斯先生
Mr. Hawkins.
把地图给我
The map if you please.
啊
Ah.
墨菲
Morph!
墨菲，地图呢？
Morph, where's the map?!
你说真的？！它还在船上？？？
Are you serious?! It's back on the ship?
让那水滴别再吵了
Stifle that blob and get low.
我们的伙伴来了
We've got company.
我们得找个好地方防守
We need a more defensible position.
霍金斯先生，前面探路
Mr. Hawkins, scout ahead.
遵命，船长
Aye, Captain.
-哦！ -小心点，小心点！
-Unh! -Steady, steady.
现在，看看这个
Now, let's have a look at that.
嘘——
Shh. shh.
-啊！ -啊！
-Aah! -Aah!
哦，真是太神奇了
Oh, this is fantastic!
终于来了一个 炭组织结构的东西来救我了
A carbon-based life form come to rescue me at last!
我只是想拥抱你
I just want to hug you and squeeze you...
把你抱得紧紧的
and hold you close to me.
好了，你还让不让我走？
All right. OK. Would you just let go of me?
哦，对不起，对不起，对不起！
Oh, sorry, sorry, sorry.
我已经一个人很久了
It's just I've been marooned for so long.
我是说，孤独真好
I mean, solitude's fine.
已经几百年了
For hundreds years
你滚远点 哈哈哈
you go a little nuts! Ha ha ha!
对不起，是不是我...
I'm sorry. Am l...
我，嗯...
I am, um...
我叫..
My name is, uh...
本！是了，我叫本
B.E.N.! Of course, I'm B.E.N.
生物电子学航海家
Bioelectronic Navigator. Oops.
-你是？ -吉姆
-And you are? -Jim.
哦，很高兴见到你，吉米
Oh, what a pleasure to meet you, Jimmy.
-是吉姆 -无论如何...
-It's Jim. -Anyway...
你看，我是个...
Look, I'm kind of
我想找个可以藏身的地方， 有海盗在追我
I got to find a place to hide, and there's pirates chasing me.
哦，海盗！ 别让我见到海盗！
Oh, pirates! Don't get me started on pirates!
我不喜欢他们！ 我记得弗林特船长。
I don't like them. I remember Captain Flint.
这家伙火气太大了
This guy had such a temper.
等等，你认识弗林特船长？
Wait, wait, wait. You knew Captain
我想他经常情绪起伏不定
I think he suffered from mood swings, personally.
我不是个医学家
I'm not a therapist, and anyway...
但我..我在散步的时候认识了你
but l--you let me know when I'm rambling.
就是说...
But that means--but wait.
你知道财宝的事？
But then you gotta know about the treasure?
-财宝？ -是的，弗林特的宝藏？
-Treasure? -Yeah, Flint's trove?
你知道的， 从几千个世界掠夺来的战利品
You know,
那是，那是...
It's--well, it's...
有那么一点点.. 一点点印象
it's all a little-- little--little fuzzy.
等等，我想起来了
Wait. I--I r-r-remember.
是的，我...财宝
I do. I--treasure!
许许多多的财宝埋在
Lots of treasure buried in the centroid--
那些机械装置的核心
centroid--centroid of the mechanism.
有一个大门 开开关关
And there was this big door opening and closing...
开开关关
and opening and closing...
弗林特船长要确定
and Captain Flint wanted to make sure...
没人可以找到他的财宝
nobody could ever get to his treasure...
所以，我帮了他
so I helped him...
啊！数据错误！重新启动！
Aah! Data inaccessible! Reboot!
本？本？本！ 重新启动....
B.E.N.? B.E.N.? B.E.N.!
重新启动！啊！你是？
Reboot! Aah! And you are?
等等，财宝怎么样了？
Wait, wait, wait!
我要说，拉里
I want to say Larry.
机械装置的核心...
The--the centroid of the mechanism, or--
对不起，我的内存已经改变
I'm sorry. My memory isn't what it used to be.
我都忘了，哈哈！ 我都忘了！
I've lost my mind. Ha ha! I've lost my mind.
你有没有找到它？
You haven't found it, have you?
哦，我丢了的那一块？ 我的主存储器电路？
Uh, my missing piece? My primary memory circuit?
本，我真的要 找一个可以藏身的地方？OK？
Look, B.E.N., I really need to find a place to hide, OK?
所以，我只是想， 你知道的，继续前进
So I'm just gonna be, you know, moving on.
哦，哦，好了，那...
Oh, uh, so, well, then...
我想这就是分别了？
I guess, uh... this is good-bye, huh?
我对我程序紊乱表示道歉
I'm sorry that I'm so dysfunctional.
好了，你走你的吧 我明白
So, uh, go ahead and... I do understand.
我明白，再见
I do. Bye-bye.
好了，你要是不想一个人呆着
Look, if you're gonna come along...
你就不要再说什么了
you're gonna have to stop talking.
呜呼！哈哈哈！ 真是太好了
Huzzah! Ha ha ha! Oh, this is fantastic!
我和我最好的伙伴要找一个...÷
Me and my best buddy are lookin' for a...
小声点
Being quiet.
你以后不要再碰我
And you have to stop touching me.
以后我都不许 碰你，跟你说话！
Touching and talking. That's my two big no-nos.
好了，现在，我想...
OK. Now, I think
听着，在我们开始找之前
Say, listen, before we go out on our big search...
嗯，您是不是先看看我的地方？
um, would you mind if we made a quick pit stop at my place?
挺急迫的，呵呵
Kind of urgent.
本，我想这正是我想要的
I think you just solved my problem.
不好意思，我这里那么乱
Uh. pardon the mess. people.
你们可以想象， 这一百多年来
You'd think in a hundred years...
这里布满了灰尘
I would've dusted a little more often...
但是，你们住进来了
but, you know, when you're batchin' it...
我会收拾好的
you tend to, uh, let things go.
啊，真是太可爱了
Aw, isn't that sweet?
我发现过去流行的罗曼史是那么动人！
I find old-fashioned romance so touching, don't you?
我们是不是要为 这对快乐的夫妻喝一杯？
How about drinks for the happy couple?
哦，哦，哦！不！
Oh, uh, ooh. Uh, no.
谢谢，我们不喝酒
Thank you, we don't drink...
还有，我们不是夫妻
and, uh, we're not a couple.
啊哈，看这些标记
Ahem. Look at these markings.
和地图上的一模一样
They're identical to the ones on the map.
我猜想这是远古文化中 的象形文字留下来的
I suspect these are the hieroglyphic remnants...of an ancient culture.
霍金斯先生
Mr. Hawkins...
别让任何人靠近
stop anyone who tries to approach. Ohh!
是的，是的，现在听我说
Yes, yes. Now listen to me...
不要操心指挥的事， 安静的躺一会儿
stop giving orders for a few milliseconds and lie still.
不错的建议，博士
Very forceful, Doctor.
继续，说点别的
Go on. Say something else.
嘿，看那儿，还有几个你们的朋友
Hey. Iook! There's some more of your buddies!
嗨，伙计们！ 我们在这儿！
Hey, fellas! We're over here, fellas!
哦哦哦！
Oh! Uhh! Ooh! Ohh!
不要浪费子弹！
Stop wastin' your fire!
你们好啊，上面的人！
Hello. up there!
吉姆？
Jimbo?
你和船长他们都好吗？
If it's all right with the captain...
我跟你说句话
I'd like a short word with ya.
不是圈套
No tricks,
肯定是冲着地图来的
Come to bargain for the map, doubtless.
这个垃圾...
Pestilential...
-啊！ -船长
-Ugh! -Captain.
那就是说， 他还以为地图在我们手上？
That means...that he thinks we still have it.
啊，墨菲， 我还以为你跑哪儿去了呢
Ah, Morphy! I wondered where you was off to.
哦
Ooh.
哦，这条老腿
Oh, this poor old leg's downright snarky...
我们在船上的那次 捉迷藏之后就不中用了
since that game attack we had in the galley.
啊
Ahh.
无论你在那里听到了什么
Whatever you heard back there...
至少那些关于你的
at least the part concerning you...
我说的都是实话
I didn't mean a word of it.
那些残忍的家伙 都认为我变的心软了
Had that bloodthirsty lot thought I'd gone soft...
他们会把我们两个都杀了
they'd have gutted us both.
听着，如果我们处理得当
Listen to me. If we play our cards right...
有了这些钱， 我们可以去当国王了
we can both walk away from this rich as kings.
-是吗？ -呵呵呵
-Yeah? -Ha ha ha.
你把地图给我
You get me that map...
哦
and, uh...
财宝中的很大一部分， 就是你的了
an even portion of the treasure is yours.
孩子
Boy.
你在船上说的那些 冠冕堂皇的话都是真心的吗？
You are really something.All that talk of greatness...
让我看到了希望... 呵呵，真是可笑
Iight coming off my sails... what a joke.
看着我，吉姆
Now, just see here, Jimbo--
我想，至少
I mean, at least
要坚持下去，是不是？
Stick to it, right?
对了，那就是我要做的
Well, that's just what I'm gonna do.
我会让你永远看不到
I'm gonna make sure that you never see...
我的那些财宝
one drabloon of my treasure!
那些财宝是属于我的！
That treasure is owed me,
好了，那你就试着 不要用我的地图，去找到它吧
Well, try to find it without my map, by thunder!
哦，你还不知道 怎么发挥你的斗志是不是？
Oh, you still don't know how to pick your fights, do you, boy?
好，看着我
Now, mark me.
你有两个选择： 天亮之前把地图给我
Either I get that map by dawn tomorrow...
或是协助我， 否则，我会用船上的大炮
or so help me, I'll use the ship's cannons...
把你们炸烂！
to blast ya all to kingdom come!
墨菲，跟我走
Morph, hop to it.
马上过来！
Now!
哦，见鬼！
Oh, blast it!
先生们
Gentlemen...
我们必须呆在一起， 还有...
we must stay together and...
还有...哦
and...ohh.
还有什么？什么？
And what? What?!
我们必须呆在一起， 还有什么？
We must stay together and what?!
博士，你的眼睛真迷人
Doctor,
她已经神智不清了
She's lost her mind!
哦，你应该赶紧帮帮她
Well, you gotta help her.
该死，吉姆，我是个 天文学家，不是医生
Dang it, Jim. I'm an astronomer, not a doctor.
我是说，我是个博士
I mean, I am a doctor,
我有博士头衔， 但那不是一回事儿
I have a doctorate. It's not the same thing.
这博士头衔救不了人
You can't help people with a doctorate.
你怎么只是坐在那里， 也不来帮忙？
You just sit there, and you're useless.
好了，博士
It's OK, Doc.
没事的
It's all right.
是的，博士！ 吉姆知道怎么离开这里。
Yeah, Doc! Jimmy knows exactly how to get out of this.
只有吉姆能想到这些办法
It's just Jimmy has this knowledge of things.
吉姆，有主意了吗？
Jim, any thoughts at all?
没有地图，我们就完蛋了
Without the map, we're dead.
我们想要逃走， 肯定是死
If we try to leave, we're dead.
-呆在这里... -我们死定了
-lf we stay here-- -We're dead!
我们死定了！我们死定了！
We're dead! We're dead!
好了，我想吉姆要静下来想想。
Well, I think that Jimmy could use a little quiet time. Heh.
所以，我要从后门出去了
So I'll just slip out the back door.
-后门？ -是的
-Back door? -Oh, yeah.
我从这儿可以轻松逃走
I get this delightful breeze through here...
我想这很重要
which I think is important...
因为在朋友之间活动...
because ventilation among friends--
哇，这是什么？
Whoa. What is all this stuff?
你是说那些远处的机器
You mean the miles and miles of machinery that run...
在行星中是怎么运转的吗？
through the entire course of the inside of this planet?
你在说什么？
Not a clue.
博士，博士， 我想我找到出口了
Hey, Doc! Doc! I think I found a way out of here!
不，不，吉姆，等等 船长让我们呆在一起
No, no. Jim, wait.
-我会回来的 -冲啊！
-I'll be back. -Cannonball!
呜呼！
Woof.
-有什么计划？ -嘘，本，安静！
-So, what's the plan? -Shh. B.E.N., quiet.
好了，是这样
OK, here it is.
我们偷偷回到船上， 毁掉激光炮
We sneak back to the Legacy, disable the laser cannons...
把地图带回来
and bring back the map.
计划听起来很不错
That's a good plan.
我喜欢。 只是..
I like that plan. The only thing is...
我想我们要怎么回去？
I'm wondering, how do we get there?
用那个
On that.
哦
Ooh.
Oop?
啊！ -本，嘘！
Aah! -B.E.N.. shh!
对不起，对不起，对不起
Sorry. sorry. Sorry.
好了，我去拿地图， 你呆在这里！
OK, I'll get the map. You wait here.
收到，吉米。 我会看着激光炮的！
Roger, Jimmy. I'll neutralize laser cannons, sir!
本！本！
B.E.N.! B.E.N.!
哟呼，哟呼 我也过上海盗生活了
Yo-ho. yo-ho. a pirate's life for me
破坏激光炮。 我应该怎么做呢？
Disable a few laser cannons. What is the big deal?
我要做的只是找到那条线
All we gotta do is find that one little wire.
哦，我的妈
Oh, mama.
就是你了
Yes.
坏了，本，坏事了
Bad, B.E.N. Bad.
好了，修好了
OK, fixing.
那愚蠢的机器人 会害死我们的
That stupid robot's gonna get us all...killed.
服务生！
Cabin boy.
啊！
Aah!
喔，OK，不着急
Whoops. OK. don't panic.
吸气，呼气
Breathing in... breathing out...
-啊！ -呣？
-Aah! -Hmm?
啊！
Raah!
这条应该是激光炮的了
This has gotta be cannons.
完了，不是
Maybe not.
啊！
Rraar!
呵呵
Heh heh.
过来，过来，过来
Come on, come on, come on.
不！
No!
哦，好极了！
Oh, yes.
记得跟埃柔先生问好
Do say hello to Mr. Arrow.
啊！
Rraar!
你自己跟他说吧！
Tell him yourself!
啊——！
Aah!
给我回去， 你这淘气的插头！
Back you go, you naughty plug! Oh!
哦！
Unh!
墨菲？
Morph?
激光炮已经破坏
Laser cannons disconnected...
吉米船长！
Captain Jimmy, sir!
并不是很难
Gee, that wasn't so tough.
博士，博士！醒醒！
Doc! Doc, wake up!
我找到地图了
I got the map.
干得好，吉姆 谢谢你帮我
Fine work, Jimbo.
孩子，谢谢你帮我们找到那条路
Thanks for showing us the way, boy.
啊！
Aah!
这堆烂铁是什么玩意儿？
What's this sorry stack of metal?!
不要碰我的脸！
Not the face!
吉姆，你跟我一样
You're just like me, Jimbo.
你讨厌失败
Ya hates to lose.
怎么回事？
What the devil's the...
打开它
Open it.
我得开始工作了
I'd get busy.
看到没，多么神奇啊
Oh, the powers that be. Would you look?
哈哈哈哈
Ha ha ha ha!
绑紧他让他们一起呆着， 直到我们...什么？
Tie him up and leave him with the others till we--what?
你要地图
You want the map...
就把我带上
you're taking me, too.
呣
Hmm.
把他们都带走
We'll take 'em all.
哦
Unh.
没事，墨菲，没事的
It's OK, Morph. It's OK.
吉米，我不知道你为什么...
Jimmy, l--I don't know about you...
我看到我的一生在我眼前滑过
but I'm starting to see my life pass in front of my eyes.
至少，那是我的一生
At least, I think it's my life.
我和一个叫着卢皮的机器人跳过舞？
Was I ever dancing with an android named Lupe?!
本，嘘
B.E.N., shh.
还没完
This isn't over yet.
伙计们，我们越来越靠近了
We're gettin' close. Iads.
我闻到了财宝的味道... 它就在前面
I smell treasure a-waitin'.
哦？
Huh?
在哪儿？
Where is it?
我什么都没看到！ 狗屎，怎么什么都没有？
I see nothing! One great, big stinking hunk of nothing!
怎么回事，吉姆？
What's going on, Jimbo?
我不知道， 我打不开了
I don't know. I can't get it open.
我们早就不该跟着这小子了！
We should've never followed this boy!
嘿！
Hey!
我劝你最好
I'd suggest you get...
把那东西弄好！快点！
that gizmo going again. and fast!
把他杀了，剖开他的肚子！
Let's rip his gizzard right out right now!
把他从山崖上扔下去！
Throw him off the cliff!
哦，原谅他吧
Oh, have mercy.
星云图？
The Lagoon Nebula?
那只是星系中的一部分
But that's halfway across the galaxy.
有个大门
A big door...
开开关关
opening and closing.
让我看看
Let's see.
金纳皮斯（地名）
Kinapis.
蒙特里莎空间站
Montressor spaceport.
弗林特就是这么做的
So that's how Flint did it.
他用这个入口 到世界各地去掠夺财宝的！
He used this portal to roam the universe stealing treasure.
他把它们都藏到哪儿去了呢？
But where'd he stash it all?
那个该死的财宝在哪儿？
Where's that blasted treasure?!
财宝！财宝！
Treasure! Treasure!
它被埋在...
It's buried in the--
埋在机器的中央核心处
Buried in the centroid of the mechanism.
如果这个行星就是那个机器
What if the whole planet is the mechanism...
财宝就埋在行星的中央
and the treasure is buried in the center of this planet?
太令人失望了， 我们怎么样才能到那里？
And how in blue blazes are we supposed to get there?
只要打开右边的门就可以了
Just open the right door.
等等我！等等我！
Wait for me! Wait for me!
从数千个世界掠夺来的战利品
The loot of a thousand worlds.
我们要一只更大的船！
We are going to need a bigger boat!
这怎么看起来这么眼熟？
This is all seeming very familiar.
为什么？
I can't remember why.
本，跟我来
B.E.N., come on.
我们离开这里， 但不能空手离开
We're getting out of here, and we're not leaving empty-handed.
但是，但是，吉米，吉米！
But--but, Jimmy! Jimmy!
我这一生的追求
A lifetime of searching.
最后
And at long last...
我终于找到了
I can touch it.
你没觉得奇怪吗？
Do you know what's strange?
我没法阻止这件事情发生，吉米
I can't tell you how frustrating this is, Jimmy...
因为有些想法...
'cause there's something just--
在我的脑子里盘旋不去
it's nagging at the back of my mind.
啊！
Aah!
-弗林特船长？ -还是个人形！
-Captain Flint? -ln the flesh!
哦，还保持完好
Well, s-sort of,
或者说是像个人形
or anything that--that--that resembles flesh...
不是的
that's not there.
怎么这么奇怪？ 你看出来了吗？
And yet it's so odd. you know?
我记得有些很恐怖的事
I remember there was something horrible...
弗林特不想任何人知道...
Flint didn't want anyone else to know...
但是我就是想不起来是什么
but I--I just can't remember what it was.
哦，一件很恐怖的事情...
Oh, a mind
本，我想我找到你的脑子了
B.E.N.,
别动
Hold still.
啊！吉米，你的手太冰了
Aah! Jimmy, your hands are very, very cold.
哇！
Whoa!
你好啊
Hello.
哦，吉米，我在想...
You know, uh, Jimmy, I was just thinking...
我在想...
I was just think--
我的记忆全回来了
It's all flooding back! All my memories!
对了，弗林特把我的存储器电路拔下来
Right up until Flint pulled my memory circuits...
我就无法告诉 别人他设下的陷阱！
so I could never tell anybody about his booby trap!
-说什么？ -啊？
-Speaking of which... -Huh?
弗林特要保证...
Flint wanted to make sure...
没人可以偷走他的财宝
that nobody could ever steal his treasure...
所以，他控制了整个行星
so he rigged this whole planet...
它会把你炸得比卡勒希安风筝还高
to blow higher than a Kalepsian kite!
快跑，吉米！快逃命吧！
Run, Jimmy! Run for your life!
你回去帮船长和博士！
You go back and help the captain and Doc!
如果我5分钟之后还没回去 你们就先走
If I'm not there in 5 minutes,
我不会离开我的朋友，吉米
I am not leaving my buddy Jimmy.
除非他这么看着我
Unless he looks at me like that.
再见，吉姆
Bye, Jim!
不！不！哦！不！哦！不！
No! No! Oh, no! Oh, no!
不！啊！
No! Aah!
-啊！ -啊！
-Aah! -Aah!
回来，笨蛋！
Come back here, ya blighters!
我这一生都想要 一次像这样的冒险
All my life, I dreamed of an adventure like this.
哦，对不起
I'm just sorry...
我不能好好的帮你
I couldn't have been more helpful to you.
哦，别傻了
Oh, don't be daft.
其实，你已经帮了我很多
You've been very helpful. Truly.
我觉得自己就像 一个无能的家伙
I feel like such a useless weakling...
我没用多大劲啊
with abnormally thin wrists.
对不起，海盗先生
Excuse me, brutish pirate.
对了，就是你，我有个问题
Yes, you. I have a question.
你的身材对于你那小小的脑袋
Is it that your body is too massive...
是不是太过于臃肿了？
for your teeny-tiny head...
或者说是你的脑袋对于你壮硕的身躯
or is it that your head is too teeny-tiny...
太过渺小了？
for your big, fat body?
我要好好教训你！
I pummel you good!
是的，我想你会这么做的。 但这之前
Yes, I'm sure you will, but before you do...
我还有一个问题。 这是你的吗？
I have one more question. Is this yours?
哦
Uhh...
是的！墨菲， 我们就要出去了！
Yes! Morph, we are so out of here!
啊，吉姆！
Ah. Jimbo!
你真是世界的第七大奇迹！
Aren't you the seventh wonder of the universe?
退回去！
Get back!
我喜欢你，小伙子 我远道而来
I like you, lad, but I've come too far...
你却阻扰我拿回我的财宝
to let you stand between me and me treasure.
啊！
Aah!
哦，不，哦，不要！
Oh, no, you don't!
什么？
What?
吉姆
Jimbo.
抓住了
Reach for me now!
抓住！
Reach!
我...我够不着！
I--I can't!
啊！
Aah!
我...
I...
哦，我简直就是个疯子！
Oh, blast me for a fool!
啊！
Aah!
席尔瓦，你放弃了？
Silver, you gave up?
它困扰了我一生，吉姆！ 我会克服的！
Just a lifelong obsession, Jim. I'll get over it.
欢迎你回来，吉米！
Aloha. Jimmy!
快点！只剩2分34秒
Hurry, people! We got exactly two minutes...
行星就要爆炸了
and thirty-four seconds till planet's destruction!
做的很好，博士
You're doing fine, Doctor.
现在让它放松一点， 慢慢来，慢慢来！
Now ease her over gently--gently!
啊！我们呆在行星上都比这好
Aah! We were better off on exploding planet!
赶紧让我们离开这里，金属人！
Take us out of here, metal man!
遵命，船长
Aye, Captain!
船长，你简直就是神女下凡...
Captain, you dropped from the heavens in the nick of--
把讨好的话跟法官说吧，席尔瓦
Save your claptrap for the judge, Silver!
导弹尾部被破坏了
Missile tail demobilized,
推进器只剩30％的能量
Thrusters at only 30% of capacity.
30％？就是说，我们...
30%? That means we're--
我们无法在行星爆炸之前离开了
We'll never clear the planet's explosion in time.
-调头回去。 -什么？
-We gotta turn around. -What?
那里有个入口， 我们可以从那里离开
There's a portal back there. It can get us out of here!
对不起，吉姆。 那个入口还没打开
Pardon me. Jim. but didn't that portal open...
回到火一般的地狱？
onto a raging inferno?!
是的，我要把更改入口
Yes, but I'm gonna change that.
打开另外一个门
I'm gonna open a different door.
船长，真的吗？ 我觉得那太不可思议
Captain, really, I don't see how this is possible--
照着他说的做
Listen to the boy!
离行星爆炸还有1分20秒
One minute, twenty-nine seconds till planet's destruction!
-我们还要怎么做？吉姆？ -想想怎么绑住这东西！
-What do you need, Jim? -Just some way to attach this.
好的，后退，后退一点！
All right. Stand back. Stand back, now.
可以走了
There you go.
好了，不管发生什么
OK. Now,
把飞船直接冲向入口
keep the ship heading straight for that portal.
还剩58秒
Fifty-eight seconds!
好了，你们听到他说的了
Well, you heard him!
调头
Get this blasted heap turned 'round!
博士，把船头对准入口
Doctor,
遵命，船长
Aye, Captain.
向右，右边！
Go to the right! The right!
我知道，我知道！ 我只是在试试
I know, I know!
25秒！
Twenty-five seconds!
不！不！
No! No!
加油，小伙子！
Come on, lad.
17秒！
Seventeen seconds!
7...
Seven...
6...5...4...
six... five... four...
3...2...
three...two...
哇！吔！
Wow! Y eah!
你成功了，吉米！
You done it. Jimmy!
你成功了！哈哈哈！
You done it, boy! Ha ha ha!
我早说过了这孩子很出色！
Didn't I say the lad had greatness in him?
太好了
Unorthodox,
我很荣幸把你推荐给
I'd be proud to recommend you...
星际学院， 他们需要一个像你这样的人
to the interstellar academy. They could use a man like you.
等着吧， 你妈妈听到这个肯定很高兴！
Just wait until your mother hears about this!
那当然，我们不用再为生计犯愁了
Of course, we may downplay the life-threatening parts.
吉米，这真是终生难忘的时刻
Jimmy, that was unforgettable!
我知道你不喜欢我碰你
I know you don't like touching...
但是，准备好， 我要好好的拥抱你
but get ready for a hug, big guy, 'cause I gotta hug ya!
哈哈哈！
Ha ha ha ha!
嘿，你也回过来抱我了
Hey, you hugged me back.
哦，我发誓不再哭的
Oh, I promised myself I wouldn't cry.
你们谁有纸巾？
Does anyone have a tissue?
-墨菲，我们做标记！ -我知道
-Morphy, we gotta make tracks. -I know.
你不会离开的，是不是？
You never quit. do you?
啊，吉姆！哈哈
Ah, Jimbo! Ha ha!
我只是检查一下，看看...
I was merely checking to make sure...
看看我们最后 一艘船是不是完好无损！
our last longboat was safe and secure.
呣！
Mmm.
哦
Well...
应该绑紧了
that should hold it.
呵呵，我教得很好啊
Heh heh heh. I taught you too well.
如果你不介意， 我可不想进监狱
If you don't mind, we'd just as soon avoid prison.
小墨菲在这里自由自在
Little morphy here, he's a free spirit.
关在笼子里， 它会很伤心的
Being in a cage, it'd break his heart.
哦！
Ohh!
小伙子，跟我一起走吧
What say you ship out with us, lad?
你和我
You and me,
只有我们，没人约束我们
full of ourselves and no ties to anyone!
你知道
You know,
我原本会和你一起走的
I would've taken you up on that offer in a second...
但是，哦，我有一个很好的朋友
but, uh,
但是他教过我， 我可以规划我的一生
and he taught me that I could chart my own course.
那正是我要做的
That's what I'm gonna do.
那你怎么看你的那个朋友？
And what do you see of that pal of yours?
是将来
A future.
为什么？
Why...
看看你，充满了活力
Iook at ya, glowing like a solar fire.
你会很出色的，吉姆
You're something special, Jim.
你会很有成就的
You're gonna rattle the stars, you are.
我的机器眼睛要加点润滑油了
Got a bit of grease in this cyborg eye of mine.
哦，嘿，墨菲， 我们还会再见的，OK？
Oh, hey, Morph. I'll see ya around, OK?
还会再见的！
See ya around.
墨菲，我要你做件事！
Morphy, I got a job for ya.
你给我好好盯着这个小子
I need you to keep an eye on this here pup.
你愿意帮我吗？
Will ya do me that little favor?
遵命，船长！
Aye-aye, Captain.
哦，还有件事
Oh, and one more thing.
这是给你妈妈的
This is for your dear mother...
让她重建她的旅馆！
to rebuild that inn of hers.
别再惹麻烦了，老家伙！
Stay out of trouble, ya old scalawag.
哈哈，吉姆，小伙子
Why, Jimbo, lad...
我做过什么吗？
when have I ever done otherwise?
哦！
Oh!
（歌词） 沐浴着阳光，我沉醉在这里的一切
It's good to see the sun and feel this place
从未有如此强烈的家的感觉
This place I never thought would feel like home
我胆怯
And I ran forever
远远逃离
Far away
总以为我要在这里孤独终结
And I always thought I'd end up here alone
缘何一切突然转变
Somehow the world has changed
我回来了
And I've come home
带回了，他们从你身上抢走的
To give you back the things they took from you
找到了你的感觉
And I feel you now
我不再孤单
I'm not alone
我总能感觉到你的存在
I always know where you are
我看着我自己
When I see myself
我总能感觉到你的存在
I always know where you are
你的存在
Where you are
我发现总有些事情
And I found something that was always there
它总会在你发现之前伤害你
Sometimes it's got to hurt before you feel
现在，我长大了，我不会再倒下
But now I'm strong. and I won 't kneel
感谢所有爱护我的人们
Except to thank who's watching over me
现在我感觉我如此强大
And somehow I feel so strong
我已不再是
And I've begun to be the one
从前的我
I never thought I'd be
我能真切的感觉到你
And I feel you now
我不再孤独
I'm not alone
我总能感觉到你的存在
I always know where you are
我看着我自己
And when I see myself
我总能感觉到你的存在
I always know where you are
你的存在
Where you are
现在一切都如此的美丽
Now it's all so clear
我坚信
And I believe
我能克服一切困难
That everything's been opened up to me
我真切的感觉到你
And I feel you now
我不再孤独
I'm not alone
我清楚的知道
I always know
我总能感觉到你的存在
I always know where you are
我看着我自己
And when I see myself
我总能感觉到你的存在
I always know where you are
我沐浴着阳光
And when I feel the sun
我总能感觉到你的存在
I always know where you are
我看着我自己
And when I see myself
我总能感觉到你的存在
I always know where you are
你的存在
Where you are
谢谢观赏